Brian:// Miranda Rodríguez

<web developer>

(+52) 55 2763 7327 brianmiranda@outlook.com b0zk0.github.io

About me

Web developer and internet researcher based in Mexico City. I'm also well-versed in UX design and mobile-first development, and I also do research on various online topics, particularly about internet culture, community moderation, misinformation, political activism, internet censorship, open-source software, DRM, platform policy/governance, online communities, online harassment, and the various intersections of mental health and social media.

Education

JAN 2011 - MAY 2014 Universidad Tecnológica de México

Licenciatura en Diseño Gráfico

JUL 2015 - NOV 2016 Universidad Tecnológica de México

Seminario en Diseño Multimedia

JUL 2018 - NOV 2018 codecademy.com

Build Websites from Scratch Pro Intensive Course

JAN 2020 - APR 2020 coderhouse.com.mx Curso de Desarrollo UX/UI

Hobbies & Interests

Hobbies:

- Dancing
- Reading
- Bullet journaling
- Deltiology
- Playing guitar and piano
- Hiking/Camping
- Videogames
- Analogue photography

Interests:

- World affairs
- Internet culture
- Game development

Skills & Toolkit

Technical:

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- · React.is
- Angular
- Bootstrap
- · Node.js
- MySQL
- Lua
- · Git Workflow

Design:

- · Adobe XD, Figma and Sketch
- Adobe CC (mainly Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects and Dreamweaver)

UI/UX research:

- User Interviews
- Qualitative/quantitative survey design and analysis
- Workshop design

Soft skills:

- Problem solving
- Critical thinking
- · Project management
- · Team player
- Fast learner

Languages:

- · English (Native)
- · Spanish (Native)
- Portuguese (Conversational)

Experience

FEB 2012 - AUG 2014 Magicorp México

Old Film Restoration Technician

Digital film restoration using Blackmagic DaVinci Revival. Removed problems such as film grain, dust, dirt and scratches, flicker, and warping from bad film splices.

OCT 2014 - OCT 2015

Muv Lab

2D Animator Internship

Pre-production, scriptwriting, storyboarding and animatics. 2D animation using Toon Boom Harmony and Adobe After Effects. Post-production.

NOV 2015 - APR 2018

Manatí Media

Motion Graphic Designer

Motion graphic work for marketing agency. Promotional videos, information screens, internal communication videos for companies, among other things.

DEC 2018 - JUL 2021

Memórica México / Presidencia de la República Multimedia Design Head of Area

Front-end development and implementation on memoricamexico.gob. Used various technologies, including JavaScript and Bootstrap to help create a government website for historical documents. Designed site ensuring UI/UX feasibility.

DEC 2021 - MAR 2022

PepsiCo, GBS Frito-Lay North America Jr. Multimedia Web Designer

Adaptation of existing visuals for digital tool kits, social media posts, digital ads and other marketing materials for the Frito-Lay North America brand portfolio.

MAY 2022 - OCT 2024 Cafebrería El Péndulo

Web Designer

Site maintenance as well as redesign of certain sections. Also ran email marketing strategy.

References

Felipe Cortina Latapí

Managing Director and Founder // Manatí Media y Axfel S.C. fcortina@axfel.com

Kassia Frida Rubi Estrella

Brand Content Manager // PepsiCo kassia.fr@outlook.com

María Angélica Santa María Daffunchio

Head of Design // Memórica México / Presidencia de la República angie.smd@gmail.com

Aida Fernanda Jiménez Ruvalcaba

Graphic Designer // Cafebrería El Péndulo paidajicama@gmail.com